foreign
[Music]
and today we have one such influencer
life influencer
meet an extraordinary achiever hailing
from meerut and currently residing in
Delhi
he is a B Tech graduate from Maharaja
agrasen Institute of Technology and
holds an MBA from Delhi School of
economics
notably he is a CFA Charter holder and a
certified financial planner
married to himani Jain for six years he
is a proud father to Aryan who's four
years old and Sharia who is four months
old
Beyond his professional Brilliance he
embodies patience honesty and ambition
in his exceptional Journey he has earned
a first-time star Club this year he has
been consistently securing mdrt right
from a second year of business Inception
furthermore his credentials are
absolutely impeccable
certified financial planner financial
planning Standards Board of India
titanium advisor ICICI share Prudential
life insurance ranked 4 pan India in
term insurance business chartered
financial analyst cdfa Institute USA
awarded best analyst for the year
2016-2017 gold advisor ICICI Lombard
health insurance and Gold Award holder
in Bloomberg aptitude test ladies and
gentlemen join me in welcoming the
luminary Prince Jen to life influencers
thanks for the wonderful introduction
Prince a very very warm welcome to you
to life influences
how are you doing this morning I'm doing
absolutely great absolutely great so
let's begin with the very first one
which is early life family and growing
up
so Prince please uh tell us something
about your childhood your life in meerut
and how life was growing up what was it
like back then
still uh we used to live in a small town
that is 30 kilometers away from meerut
so it was a gathering of approximately
10 000 people in the entire vicinity I
lived there for my first 11 years then
we shipped it to Delhi way back in 2004.
so it used to be a very amazing kind of
title that people uh you know enjoy uh
from Villages because everyone in the
colony is your friend irrespective of
age they used to celebrate even the
smallest of the festivals and you will
be able to you know feel that uh warmth
feel that uh Aura around that something
is coming up next and the preparation
will start like one month in advance
unlike daily even though people are very
physio to themselves so it was it was
amazing it was amazing so uh Prince tell
us what values have you learned in um in
your small town which is close by meerut
and how have those values helped you
grow and Excel in your life's journey so
as I talked because people are very much
you know involved in each other so they
are like if something is happening to
one person it is happening to the entire
area so you you get a lot of empathy you
learn okay how to understand what person
is going for uh what is happening with
the other person and apart from that uh
it also helps you in terms of building
relationship you know how to be vocal
about other person uh needs and all
those things so that is that is what we
are actually doing in the business also
we have to understand other person needs
and we have you know build it upon build
upon it and build it from there so that
is uh that is what I feel that my
society and my upbringing has you know
given me uh my next question to you is
how was your school life I was very
average kind of a student when I was in
school and when I joined my college
graduation specifically I was a back
venture so it was the worst thing that I
wanted to you know uh go and join it was
third year of my b-day when I actually
took my career seriously and started
preparing for cat and that was the time
that I would call that I became from a
backbender to a studious kind of person
I let's get to know something about you
and your better half so please tell us
when did you meet Mrs himani Jen so it's
a very interesting and a filmy kind of
story so my her father used to be
childhood buddies so we belong to the
same Hometown and they my father and
father you know went to school together
and they have been together ever since
so one day they sat together and you
know decided
again sort of things and I was just 18
or 19 I think and even we knew each
other our entire life even we have a
picture of ourselves and I was one she
was six months old and like and that
Journey has been together but when our
family proposed this to us and we said
okay well this is who you who have to
decide later on also so we were young We
Were Young so we were told at 18 or 19
that this is how it is going to be uh do
you agree and we said yes and that is
how the things are progressed from there
there is such an interesting story
that's is that uh like you said that
proper family dialogue is
life has been amazing we are so happy to
know that you have two boys two
beautiful boys in your life now and
congratulations on being so Lucky in
Love and Marriage thank you thank you
thank you please describe your marriage
in three words just three words it was
made for each other it's very simple
that is so beautiful that's four hours
but I'm gonna give it to you that's
truly beautiful
thank you let's move on to our next
question now since we've spoken about
himani how would you describe your
relationship with your children they're
quite young right now I think Arya is
more close to her mother but I'm trying
to you know build up my relationship now
because it's getting uh more uh mature
now please tell us uh how different has
it been with sharya growing up than
Aryan and are they similar in some ways
or the other so their polls about Aryan
used to be that kid the ideal kid but
surely is that another level kind of
things he's very cranky he cries all the
time okay so now let's move on to our
next segment of this chat which is
Pursuit of Happiness so friends please
tell us how did your journey with life
insurance start
so I understood I understood the
importance of life insurance quite early
in my life so uh when I was learning
about financial planning what are the
nuances of it so you cannot prepare a
financial plan without having a right
kind of foundation I call life insurance
is a vaccination to financial plan if
something is to happen to you know the
breadwinner of the family how the
remaining family is going to survive so
for that particular reason I was very
keen and it was a thoughtful decision
that when I will be starting my own
business so though two kind of
Association I need to have one is life
insurance one is health insurance they
provided protection when things are not
going as per your plan so that is that
is when uh when I started you know
registered for my you know corporate and
my company I enrolled for uh ICICI
Prudential for life insurance and ICC
Lombard for health insurance because uh
the kind of service they provided is
imaginable I have seen that even before
joining the the company so let's uh
forward our next question is knowing
that you've completed seven years in in
this journey what are the challenges
that you faced and how have these
challenges helped you to grow personally
so uh the biggest challenge is the age
part because I'm you know sitting in
Industry working in Industry on my own
which where experience is highly valued
and apart from that all we deal is money
like where to invest how much to invest
when do we draw and all sort of things
so people uh will need to you know find
it hard to you know trust a young boy
with all their hard-earned money had it
been me on the other side I would have
you know say had the same kind of
problem so I was 26 or 25 when I started
my business so uh I used to grow my you
know beard have some you know even more
mature so it was a totally different
kind of thing but I don't want to look
like that I put on weight intentionally
okay I should be looking like a little
bit mature kind of person so there's a
person didn't trust me I had knowledge I
had the work experience and all but it
was that so uh working working in this
domain particularly has not been easy
but it was like you follow the rules you
work hard you give it your best some
days will be good some days will be bad
but things will automatically fall in
place if you've heard in the right
direction so but that is how it has been
I've been very blessed to you know have
uh so many good friends who you know
took that leap of faith who started out
when I had nothing to show but I promise
that we will serve to the best of our
abilities and all those things and uh
they started out things went well things
were working fine and
I think I have done a decent kind of job
in terms of satisfying my clients and uh
helping them grow their wealth in the
same time we have not done a decent job
we've done incredibly well believe me
Prince When I say this and uh like you
said like it discussed uh prior we
people generally have this perception
that when it comes to the when it comes
to financial planning it has your
planner has to be older in age but it is
so good to say that um young people like
you are debunking this myth that no your
financial Planet need not to be old even
young individuals like you can help them
grow their businesses and their finances
and once again congratulations uh to you
on starting on so early in life and now
wait what is that one best moment that
you have achieved while working in life
insurance
so there are number of them but uh for
achievement if I talk about when I
qualified my first mdrd it was a big
moment for me because I never had
planned that I will be qualifying
something like mdrt and when I entered
my life insurance industry I didn't knew
that there is something that is known by
the name India so when I qualified it
cleared it and I got a call from my
manager that your mdid is done and then
I started looking it up okay what it is
and I was I was like on another level
that's amazing so now Prince let's move
on to our next segment which is movement
of Truth so very first question in this
segment is share with us a moment of
challenge or weakness which you might
have faced in your life and how you
overcame it
so it is again when I started my
business four years back uh it was early
business I was not having any kind of
you know road map or plan that this is
how we are going to go about it I didn't
know whether I will succeed or not I
just had that self-cleve that I have to
you know give it this much time I have
to focus on these things and let the uh
business take its course of action in
the very second year we encountered
covet everything fall apart and it's a
entire country worship the entire world
version everything was happening over
his room and people are not people do
not know whether they will be having
like income coming their way next month
so how do you can talk about uh talk to
them about the investment part so it was
a very uh challenging kind of phase so
for the first three months so we sticked
on the rules we follow the rules key uh
okay this is the hard time okay let's
focus on the fundamentals let's focus on
what you are supposed to do what is in
your control and there are things that
are beyond your control there's no point
in worrying about them and things you
know Paul and that is again we focus
those three months we uh uh focused and
followed a number of rules that actually
you know eventually panned out well and
again so we recovered from that
that's so good to know and yes
especially when you don't have a road
map in the beginning and when something
like covered hits it's important to keep
going so my follow-up question is
similar to that what is that one thing
that motivates you to keep pushing
yourself to Achieve Beyond Excellence
year after year so it is the
satisfaction that you get because uh as
I've said life is work and work is life
I don't feel that I'm working a single
day if your work becomes a burden on you
then you are exhausted but my work never
exhausts me I I can work like 16 hours
18 hours because all I have to do is
speak to clients understand their big
ones help them out and when you you know
really help your clients you know
identifying their blind spots okay what
it is that they are not looking at what
is that they are not uh doing directly
what it is that they can do better that
can help them in terms of gaining more
time more time with their family more
time with uh for outings and all those
things that that really you know uh
gives me a kick here you are in the
right direction well life is all about
health and wealth I cannot do anything
you know focus more on more on the
health part so that that is the
financial equation that I see uh from my
angle yeah you focus on this and let
them have all the Liberty all the space
to focus on the other things that are
more important to them and that really
gives me the satisfaction uh for you
know keep going keep working keep
hustling and all those things let's move
on to our next segment which is my
Pillars of Strength so please tell us
how has your family supported you
throughout your life and your career so
there have been the foundation of
whatever I'm being able to do right now
because I got married at 24. I was
working in a corporate kind of setup
after one year I decided and I want to
quit I want to pursue civil services I
want to you know have a taste of it what
it is like because everyone says it's
very difficult and all those things are
prepared for four to six months that is
new that is when me and my wife you know
actually went for uh preparation is
studying together so after six months of
that I don't have this much patience
that I can you know rely totally on luck
and study kept on studying for three or
three years four years and without
knowing whether I will be able to make
it or not then I finally decided to
start my business and uh they give all
that freedom to me so you know you know
to test what I want to do when I want to
do it how I want to do it they've never
questioned on uh my abilities this is
not going to be the right way you should
be focusing on your work you should be
focusing on the job you should start
some other business this is like
Campbell and all those sort of things
they gave me my space so that I can
explore myself and because they always
have that thing in mind because if you
are not able to do something on your own
we will have something arranged for you
so I had that freedom that I don't have
to you know earn money on a monthly
basically recurring basis I was not
under the water the uh if these are not
working then what next I always had that
backing and that is a big support that
is a big support from the family again
my friends have been very great uh my
friend I will name him uh advith has
been the instrumental in terms of
starting my business because he was the
one when I was thinking I should be you
know rejoining my job starting my
business he was the one you are very
good at it you should be starting on
your own this is the time this is the
time I leave you uh 200 person we will
help you and he actually helped me in
terms of you know starting your resume
reaching out to more clients and to
helping with the tech part uh obviously
my my wife again after marriage a lot of
other things start coming in your
experiences increase and all those
things so she's very understanding uh
the kind of understanding and kind of
level of commitment she has towards the
relationship is unmatchable she
understands all the things she
understands what I want to do and she
gives me again that uh mental Freedom
the space
let's now move on to our next segment
which is life goals and aspirations so
Prince where do you see yourself in the
coming years and what are your goals so
as I told you that first of my first
priority right now is you know to Belt a
YouTube channel have more audience that
I can you know help out and I can reach
out to uh that is something that we have
been working on that is something that
we want to work on consistently for the
coming time now but we want to you know
automate a lot of systems that we
another client will not be you know
relying on a person sitting outside but
he can you know log on to the system and
the system will tell everything so I
want to you know whatever information
and knowledge I have I want to inculcate
that into a system into a software that
will help client in general kind of
advice so again this is a it is a goal
that I have for five years and let's see
how it panned out we are working on it
we in part we keep or you know uh
improving our existing system also so we
have now reached a very interesting
segment Prince which is called the rapid
fire round are you excited yeah um
please tell us skating or badminton
skating
favorite color red or black black any
day I'm wearing black today
or coffee tea I'm a tea man okay
yeah without another I don't drink oh me
too high five what's your high five okay
next one traveling with friends or
family family
movies you like science fiction or
thread up trailers will have a business
because I I like both science fiction
and Thriller great a Bollywood or
Hollywood Bollywood the street food of
and seafood street food in a fancy
restaurant okay last one your favorite
Corner in your house my bed actually I'm
totally exhausted where is where's my
bed so with that uh Prince we have
unfortunately come to the end of this
lovely chat session but before I
conclude uh any last words that you
would love to share with the viewers so
essentially live Insurance may you will
not find a lot of young people you know
enrolling they always think of life
insurance industry that is for side as
it you keep on doing your main work or
mainstream job and alongside big life
insurance that do not work most of the
time because I truly believe life
insurance is a very big industry in
itself so you have to work on that you
have to understand the fundamentals and
the things to fall in place for you
thank you so very much Prince that was
so wonderfully said believe me when I
say this is true all your stories have
been truly truly inspiring so many
takeaways from this chat session and I
think the biggest one for me and I'm
sure of all the viewers out there will
be your hunger to constantly keep
learning thank you for inspiring the
youth to get into this industry I on
behalf of icic Prudential life insurance
would like to salute you for being the
true Dodge bearer of life insurance for
being the ultimate beacon in the life
insurance industry our life influencer
yeah one day
my name is Nisha Shetty and this is me
signing off see you again next time on
the live influencers
thank you once again Prince thank you
Nisha thank you for having me
I've seen your success Journey from day
one and I know it is not easy for
anybody to leave their well paid job and
start their own business but you have
shown that Currys and I really
appreciate this situations
dead
foreign
[Music]